aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
Finally, after taking revenge on Ark Seijin, the Space Swordsman Lian left Earth to find his race.
마침내 아크 성인에게 복수를 마친 우주 검사 라이안은 동족을 찾아서 지구를 떠나갔다
The Dagwon left behind now have to confront the all-out attack from the Three Warugaia Brothers.
남겨진 다그온들을 기다리고 있는 것은 와르가이아 3형제에 의한 총력을 다한 공격이다
The battle is now about to begin!
싸움은 지금 시작하려 하고 있었다
A bath is best done at a bathhouse!
역시 목욕은 목욕탕이 제일이지!
This is...
이건…
Who is it?!
누구냐?
You punk!
이자식!
Did you attack me knowing that I am Geki Kuroiwa of Fuun High School?
내가 풍운 고등학교의 쿠로이와 게키라는 걸 알고도 습격한 거냐?!
Who's there?!
누구냐?!
Geki!
게키!
Hang in there, Geki!
정신차려, 게키!
An Unwanted Confrontation
바라지 않는 대결 와르가이아 성인 히도 등장
바라지 않는 대결
Warugaia Seijin Hido
Appears
와르가이아 성인 히도
등장
Moreover, Geki, you let that punk do this to you.
게다가 게키, 그렇게 당하다니!
But, he saved his life.
하지만 생명에 지장이 없어서 다행이예요
I am ashamed.
면목 없다
A man, Geki Kuroiwa, made a lifetime mistake.
사나이 쿠로이와 게키
일생의 실수를 하다니…
If Ryu wasn't there, you'd now be...
나 참, 류가 마침 거길 지나가지 않았다면 지금쯤 너는… 역시 류 선배!
나 참, 류가 마침 거길 지나가지 않았다면 지금쯤 너는…
That's my Ryu senpai!
역시 류 선배!
Oh, a red bean bread! I'll eat one, Geki!
오옷, 팥빵 발견~
먹을게, 게키
I bought that a week ago.
그거 일주일 전에 산 거야
Do you remember any characteristics of the criminal?
범인의 얼굴이나 특징은 기억 안 나?
Too bad. It was too dark.
유감이지만, 너무 어두웠어
-But...
-But?
-단지…
-단지?
Hey, Geki!
여봐, 게키
-단지…
-단지? 여봐, 게키
Don't you have any erotic magazines?
뭔가 말이지 좀 므흣~한 잡지같은 거 없냐?
Don't rummage through my things!
맘대로 보지마!
It's just my feeling, but I think the criminal is a female.
어디까지나 내 감이지만 범인은 여자인 것 같은 기분이 들어
You're awesome, Ryu senpai!
역시 류 선배!
범인은 여자인 것 같은 기분이 들어 역시 류 선배!
Female?
여자?
What?!
뭐라고?! 내가, 쿠로이와 게키가 계집애의 습격에 당했다고?!
뭐라고?!
Do you mean that I, Geki Kuroiwa, was done in by a girl?!
내가, 쿠로이와 게키가 계집애의 습격에 당했다고?!
Just forget it.
신경쓰지마
My feeling isn't always right.
내 감은 가끔 빗나갈 때도 있어 메야?
Anyway, this enemy can take down such muscle packed guy.
어쨌든, 이런 호걸을 쓰러뜨렸을 정도의 상대야
She must be a some kind of master.
상당한 실력자임에 틀림없어
Hello.
안녕하십니까
Boss, someone called Maria Tobe from Sankai High School is here to see you.
두목 산카이 고등학교의 토베 마리아란 사람이 면회왔습니다
M- Ms. Maria is?!
마, 마리아 씨가?!
-Good morning.
-We're here to see how you're doing.
-안녕
-문병 왔어, 게키
M-Ms. Maria!
마, 마리아 씨
You came to see me in particular?
몸소 문병을 오시다니…
It's just a scratch.
그냥 조금 긁힌 것 뿐이예요
You must've had quite some damage.
큰일 당했구나
그냥 조금 긁힌 것 뿐이예요 큰일 당했구나
But it's good to see you being healthy.
그치만 건강한 것 같아서 안심했어
Yeah!
네~
Hey, don't just stand there stupidly; get some cups of juice to Ms. Maria and Gaku.
이봐, 멍청히 서 있지 말고 마리아 씨와 가쿠 군에게 주스를 대령해라
Got it!
알았습니다!
Sorry to interrupt, Geki!
신경쓰이게 해서 미안하다, 게키
Uh, I'd prefer coffee...
저기, 가능하다면 전 커피 쪽이…
Yo-you guys should go back!
너, 너희들은 그만 돌아가라
Isn't it alright?
별 상관없잖아
너, 너희들은 그만 돌아가라 별 상관없잖아
Let's play trump card together!
다함께 트럼프하자
Oh, that's a good idea!
아, 그거 좋군요
Let's do that!
오옷, 하자 하자
Please teach to me too!
제게도 가르쳐 주세요
Yo- you guys!
너, 너희들…
Leaving at times like this is friendship!
이럴 때는 자리를 떠 주는게 우정이란 거잖아
Something smells.
냄새가 나
이럴 때는 자리를 떠 주는게 우정이란 거잖아 냄새가 나
So- sorry. I'll clean up right now...
죄, 죄송합니다
지금 당장 청소를…
That's not it.
그게 아니야
I feel the existence of a bad spirit.
뭔가 좋지 않은 영의 존재가 느껴져
A spirit, huh?
영…말입니까?
So, everyone, please get out.
자, 모두 밖으로 나가줘
I'll purify this place right now!
지금부터 내가 불제를 해줄게
Disappear!
사라지거라~
사라지거라~!
I'll keep my eye on Geki, just in case.
난 만일을 위해서 게키의 경호를 계속할게
Don't let your guard down.
그래, 방심하지마
Geki being targeted means that we Dagwon are also targets.
게키가 노려졌단 것은 다시말해 우리 다그온이 노려졌단 거야
I know.
응, 알고 있어
Get in.
타세요
You are...!
당신은…!
I am Luna, from Planet OOParts.
저는 혹성 오파츠의 루나
108th division of Space Police Organization.
우주 경찰 기구 제 108분서
I am under the command of the 5th patrol unit.
제 5정찰 부대에 소속되어 있습니다
Weren't you supposed to return to space after Queen Zargoss?
퀸 자고스 사건 이후 당신은 우주로 귀환했던 게…
Is this some kind of special mission?
무슨 특별한 임무입니까?
Where are we heading?
어디로 향하고 있는 겁니까?
We're here.
다 왔어요
Is that island it?
저 섬은 대체…?
What are you doing?!
무슨 짓이냐?!
Hurry and reposition the helicopter!
어서 기체를 원래대로 돌려!
Luna!
루나!
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온
Kai here.
여기는 카이
No signal...
통신 불능인가…
Looks like an abandoned resort development project.
리조트 개발에 실패한 섬이군
Where...
어디냐…
Where are you?!
어디에 있지?!
Off Limits
출입금지
Did you find Kai?
카이의 행방은 알았어?
Geki!
게키!
Are you alright with that body?
너 그런 몸으로 괜찮겠어?
I just can't sleep in this situation!
이런 중요한 때에 태평히 자고 있을 수 있겠냐!
Rai is searching with Dag Base's radar.
라이가 지금 다그 베이스의 레이더로 수색중입니다
How's it going, Rai?
어때, 라이?
It's no use. I can't find Kai senpai.
틀렸습니다 카이 선배를 포착할 수 없습니다
Hey, wasn't Dag Base supposed to be able to track all of us?
이봐, 다그 베이스는 우리가 있는 곳을 바로 볼 수 있는 게 아니었나?
Yes...
네…
But this time, some strong signal is interfering.
하지만 뭔가 강한 힘이 방해하고 있는 것 같습니다
Interference...
방해…
Anyway, let's go find him!
어쨌든 찾으러 가자
Where... where are you?
어디냐… 어디 있지?
You must've attacked Geki too!
게키를 습격한 범인도 너구나!
Why did you do this?
어째서 이런 짓을?!
Answer me, Luna!
대답해, 루나!
Luna!
루나…!
루나!
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온
Galaxy Luna!
갤럭시 루나
What's the meaning of this?!
어떻게 된 거야?!
Stop!
그만둬!
Why are you doing this?!
어째서 이런 짓을?!
My objective is...
나의 사명은…
The Purge of Dagwon!
다그온 말살!
What?!
뭐야?!
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Kai, do you hear me?
카이, 내 목소리 들려?
Kai!
카이!
Where did he disappear to?
나 참, 어디로 사라진 거야?
If you're like that...
어쩔 수 없군
Try Dagwon!
트라이 다그온
Turbo Kai!
터보 카이
Why, Luna?! Open your eyes!
어째서냐, 루나!
눈을 떠!
Shut up!
닥쳐!
Stop! Do you even know what you're doing right now?
그만둬! 자기가 뭘 하고 있는지 알고 있는 거야?!
I didn't want to be violent, but you've left me no choice!
난폭한 짓은 하고 싶지 않지만, 할 수 없군
Turbo Knuckle!
터보 너클!
Sorry, are you alright?
미안, 괜찮아?
You're...
너는…
Hido!
히도!
You should treat women more delicately.
여성은 좀 더 섬세하게 다뤄야지
What?!
뭐야?!
Luna is mine.
루나는 내 것이다
Luna!
루나!
My existence is for Lord Hido.
나의 존재는 히도 님의 것
You see?
이런 셈이지
You bastard! What have you done to Luna?!
이자식, 루나에게 무슨 짓을 했느냐?!
Luna is already my murder machine.
루나는 이미 나의 충실한 살인 머신이다
Hido, you bastard! Unforgivable!
히도 아자식!
용서치 않겠다!
What?!
아니?!
Follow him. Kill Turbo Kai.
쫓아라 터보 카이를 죽여라
Shield Smoke!
실드 스모크!
Luna!
루나!
I do not want to fight with you! You're being controlled by Hido!
너와는 싸우고 싶지 않아! 넌 히도에게 조종당하고 있는 거야!
Open your eyes, Luna!
눈을 떠, 루나!
Hido is a devil. A criminal of Space!
히도는 악마야 우주의 범죄자야!
Are you okay with being trampled by such a guy?!
그런 녀석에게 마음을 짓밟히고도 아무렇지도 않아?!
Think, Luna!
생각해내, 루나!
You are a detective who protects the peace and order of Space!
너는 우주의 평화와 질서를 지키는 우주 형사잖아!
Not to a devil... You cannot surrender your heart to Hido!
악마에게… 히도에게 마음을 내줘선 안돼!
Luna...
루나…
Luna!
루나!
You cannot disobey me.
넌 널 거역할 수 없어
You cannot be relieved from that pain.
그 고통에서 벗어날 수 없단 말이다
Your mission is to purge Dagwon!
너의 사명은 다그온 말살!
What's wrong, Luna?!
왜그래, 루나?!
My mission is...
내 사명은…
purging Dagwon!
다그온 말살!
What...?
뭐야…?
Justice is a weak thing after all.
결국 정의 따윈 어리석고 나약한 것이다
Now you see, dear Kai?
알겠니, 카이?
That's cowardly, Hido! Stop controlling Luna by force!
비겁하다, 히도! 힘을 써서 루나를 조종하는 짓은 그만둬라!
Don't make her suffer!
루나를 괴롭히지 마라!
Please! Stop it, Luna!
부탁이야! 그만둬, 루나!
Is your spirit truly under his control?
정말로 마음까지 녀석에게 지배당해버린 거야?!
Luna...
루나…
Do you hear me, Luna?
내 말 들어, 루나!
You are now desperately fighting against Hido's spell!
너는 지금 필사적으로 히도의 주박과 싸우고 있어!
Your enemy is Hido!
너의 적은 히도야!
My existence is...
나의 존재는…
... for Lord Hido.
히도 님의 것…
You're wrong!
아니야!
A person is not supposed to be controlled by someone else!
인간은 다른 누군가에게 지배당하는 존재가 아니야!
Especially by Hido!
더구나 히도 따위에게…!
My mission is...
나의 사명은…
purging Dagwon!
다그온 말살!
Wrong! Open your eyes, Luna!
아니야!
눈을 떠, 루나!
Now returning to the H. Q. of the Space Police Organization.
지금부터 우주 경찰 본부로 귀환합니다
Farewell, Brave Heroes of the Earth.
안녕, 지구의 용자들
What?!
아니?!
I will take both your body and your spirit.
넌 몸도 마음도 모두 나의 것이 될 것이다
Luna...
루나…
Your mission is purging Dagwon.
너의 사명은 다그온 말살
Understood?
알겠지?
Stop... please stop!
그만둬…
이제 그만둬!
Luna!
루나!
Are you alright?
괜찮아?
루나! 괜찮아?
Don't come near!
오지마!
Don't make me suffer anymore!
이 이상 날 괴롭히지마!
Luna!
루나!
Luna... Luna! Hang in there!
루나… 루나!
정신차려
Don't die... you can't die!
죽지마…
죽지 말라구!
Luna! Please open your eyes!
루나…
눈 좀 떠봐!
I'll save you no matter what.
반드시 구해줄게
Please... keep living!
부탁이야…
숨을 쉬어!
Luna!
루나!
Kai...
카이…
It's alright. Everything's alright.
괜찮아
이제 괜찮아
Kai...
카이…
Luna!
루나…!
Good job. Now, come.
잘했다
자, 이리와라
Stop!
기다려!
Don't go! You can't!
가지마
가면 안돼!
Hmph, you're going to die soon.
흥, 다 죽어가는 녀석이…
I told you Luna is mine.
루나는 나의 것이라고 말했을 텐데?
What's so funny?
뭐가 우습지?
Hido...
히도…
You really are the worst.
너란 녀석은 정말 최악이다
What?!
뭐야?!
I told you that you are the worst, for playing with someone else's mind by force!
힘을 써서 남의 마음을 가지고 노는 정말 최악인 녀석이라고 했다!
You punk, do you really want to die that much?
아자식, 그리도 죽고싶냐?
But I don't kill right away.
하지만 바로 죽이진 않는다
I'll beat you to death.
두들겨 패서 죽여주마
Don't die too soon. I'll play with you a bit more.
아직 죽지마라 좀 더 놀아달라구
Luna... wake up!
루나… 눈을 떠!
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
닥쳐! 닥쳐! 닥쳐!
Luna!
루나!
What an annoying brat.
시끄러운 녀석
Playtime is over!
장난은 끝이다!
The finishing blow...
끝이다…
Die!
죽어라!
What?!
아니?!
Luna...
루나…
N- no way...
마, 말도 안돼…
Hido!
히도---!
Why you-! I'll stomp you to death!
이자식!
밟아 죽여주마!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체
(融合合體)
Unforgivable!
용서 못한다!
Hido!
히도----!
S- stop it!
그, 그만둬!
Luna... Luna!
루나… 루나!
Luna!
루나!
I see.
그렇구나
This must've amplified the energy...
이게 에너지를 확산시켜서…
Wake up, Luna.
정신차려, 루나
Kai...
카이…
Forgive me, Kai.
요, 용서해줘
카이…
Don't speak. It's all alright now.
말하지마
이제 괜찮아
Lu- Luna...
루, 루나…
Come back...
돌아와라…
Please come back...
돌아와 다오…
You're mine...
넌 나의 것이다…
Hido... I am not your puppet anymore!
히도… 난 이제 너의 꼭두각시가 아니야!
Luna!
루나…!
Everyone!
얘들아!
Damn you, Dagwon!
이놈, 다그온!
I'll kill you all!
네놈들 모두 다 죽여주마!
Remember this!
기억해 둬라!
Luna! Luna!
루나, 루나!
Kai!
카이!
Are you alright?!
-괜찮아?!
-괜찮습니까?!
Luna! Luna!
루나! 루나!
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
tomaru koto nai MELODY
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
tooku kirameita
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
kaze no naka no PRISM
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
A synthesized alien, Zelma.
합성 우주인 제르마
This is the strongest alien that the Warugaia Brothers have made.
이건 와르가이아 형제가 만들어낸 최강의 우주인입니다
Don't worry.
안심해 난 새로운 합체를 할 수 있는 것 같아
안심해
I think I can do a new fusion.
난 새로운 합체를 할 수 있는 것 같아
With that, I can face any enemy!
그걸 사용하면 어떤 적이라도…
But we don't know about that fusion yet!
하지만 그 합체는 아직 미지수입니다!
We don't know what will happen to En's body!
엔의 몸에 무슨 일이 일어날지 알 수 없습니다!
But everyone is in danger!
하지만 모두가 위험해!
We gotta do it!
시험해 볼 수밖에 없어
It's too dangerous, En!
너무 위험해요, 엔!
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! The Forbidden Super Fusion
다음회 용자지령 다그온
금단의 초합체
I'll show you the power of Super Fire Dagwon!
보여주마
슈퍼 파이어 다그온의 힘을!
The Forbidden Super Fusion
금단의 초합체